Rienow, Robert; Papers ua902.009
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1939-1984; 6; 1.75 cubic ft.
  - Miscellaneous, K, 1962-1970 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous, O, 1963-1983 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, P, 1958-1983 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, R, 1963-1982 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, S, 1963-1984 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous, T, 1965-1968; 1982; 1985 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Moment in the Sun, 1969-1975 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, Accreditation Assignment, 1965 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - The Nature Conservancy, 1973 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - The New Star in the Sky, 1975 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - New York State Teachers Association, 1965 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Non Voter-Correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    (includes Clippings).
  - Of Snuff, Sin and the Senate, 1958-1963 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Of Snuff, Sin and the Senate, 1965-1969 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Our New Life With the Atom, 1958-1967 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Permissions and Publicity, 1970-1980 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Personal, 1946-1975 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Publications, 1969-1977; Undated (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Requests, 1970 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Research Foundation, 1960-1971; Undated (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - School Affairs, 1958-1964 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - School Affairs-Student Related, 1961-1963 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Speeches, 1973-1980 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Speeches and Presentations, 1969-1971; Undated (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 29)
    (includes notes and clippings).
  - Somit, Albert, "Political Science and the Study of the Future", 1969-1970 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 30)
    Includes Clippings.
  - State and Local Government Notices and Correspondence, 1954-1962 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - SUNY Albany and Related Materials: Student Letter and Transcript, 1976 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - The Test of the Nationality of Merchant Vessel, 1937-1938 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Winch, Thomas, 1971; 1983 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - World Book Encyclopedia, 1965-1981 (Box 2 (6-Correspondence), Folder 35)
- Subject Files, 1937-1980; 7; 3.67 cubic ft.
  This series is comprised of files on organizations and subjects that were of interest to Rienow. Groups include Defenders of Wildlife, Zero Population Growth, the Nature Conservancy, and Citizens to Save the Adirondack Park. Topics include deforestation and land use, wildlife protection, overpopulation, national wealth, nuclear fallout and the problems of atomic energy, and various forms of pollution. The files contain mostly notes, news clippings, articles, mailings, and publications. There are also files related to government agencies, such as the Department of the Interior and the United States National Treasury. These files consist mainly of government publications on environmental policies and issues, as well as some publications on the structures of the agencies. A few files relate to political science topics.
  - Adirondacks, 1959-1962 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Albany County Environmental Advisory Council, 1971-1972; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
    [contains clippings].
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, Bioscience (annotated), 1968 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - The Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks, Publication, 1973 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Atomic Energy, 1956-1959 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Atomic Energy, 1968-1970 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Atomic Energy Publications, Philosophical Library, Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - "Atoms for Peace", New York State Library Exhibit, 1958 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1953; 1958 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Cats, 1933; 1959; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Carthage College, President's Annual Report, 1963 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - China, Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - The Christian Science Monitor, 1939 January 11 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Committee for Economic Development, 1958 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, Program Announcements, 1963-1964 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Coordinating Governments Through Regionalism and Reform, Volume 1, 1971 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Defenders of Wildlife, 1967-1971 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Defends of Wildlife, 1978-1980 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Defenders of Wildlife Funding Proposal, 1978 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Delaware Basin Bulletin, 1960 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - "Design of Dictatorship", Davis, Undated; manuscript (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Congress Committee, Participant List, 1969 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Fallout, 1950-1959 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Fallout, 1950-1959 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Fallout, 1950-1959 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Fallout, 1950-1959 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Fallout, 1960-1965 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Follett Publishing Company, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Fluoridation of Water, 1955-1962 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Forest Conservation, 1958-1963 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Forest Preserve and Adirondack Water Supply, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Forests, 1957-1958; Undated (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Forestry, Publications, 1961-1964 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Gerrymandering, Local, County, State Districting, 1961 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - "Guide to Research in Air Pollution", U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1962 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - The Izaak Walton Magazine, 1961-1962; 1964 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Kaibab Squirrels, 1964 (Box 1 (7-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Kennedy, John F.Los Angeles Times Articles on Assassination, 1963 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - The Living Wilderness, Adirondack Park, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Man Against His Environment, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Man Against His Environment, Notes, correspondence, articles, 1969-1971 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960s (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1966-1969 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Environmental Articles and Low Proposals, 1969; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Motoring in Germany, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
    [includes Rienow travel notes].
  - The National Council of Farmer Cooperatives, Publications, 1947 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - National Parks Magazine, 1960; 1964 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Natural Resources Journal, 1961 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - The Nature Conservancy [newsletter], 1956 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - New York State Assembly, Calendar of Bills, 1963 March 28 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - North Cascades Conservation Council, Publication, 1963 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Nuclear Waste, Note Cards, ca. 1958? (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Nuclear Waste, Note Cards, ca. 1958? (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Nuclear Wastes and Accidents, 1959 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Open Space and Parks, 1966-1968 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Our New Life With the Atom, Articles on book and miscellaneous, ca. 1959 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Our New Life With the Atom, Publicity Photographs, ca. 1959 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Overpopulation, Notes, Clippings, and Proposals [folder 2 of 2], Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Pesticides and Additives, 1964-1970 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Policy Studies Journal, Policy Studies Organization, 1978 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Potomac Appalachian Trail Club Bulletin, 1968 April-1968 June (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - A Practical Manual on the Medical and Dental Use of X-Rays with Control of Radiation Hazards, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Radiation, 1955-1958 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Radiation, National Bureau of Standards, Handbook 52, Annotated, 1953 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Radiation, 1955-1958 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - The Saratoga Associates, Report, "The Environmental Base Analysis", 1978 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Science and Mathematics Teaching Center, Michigan State University, A Guide for Teaching Regional Environmental Planning, 1978 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Select Committee on National Water Sources, United States Senate, Publication, 1960 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Society of American Foresters, Publication, 1960 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - State of New York Adirondack Park Agency, Publication, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Soviet Union, 1941; 1949; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Ultraviolet Water Purification, Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - The University of the State of New York, Bulletin to the Schools, 1953 March (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - U. S. Department of Agriculture, Water Resources, Publications, 1957; 1960 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Predator Damage in the West: A Study of Coyote Management Alternatives, 1978 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - U. S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Publications, 1960 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Vichy France, 1942 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Water Pollution, Clippings and Articles, 1965-1970 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Water Pollution, Miscellaneous Articles, Drafts, Notes, and Clippings, ca. 1962 (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Water Resources, Publications, 1956-1959; Undated (Box 2 (7-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Water Supply, 1950-1969 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Water Supply, 1950-1969 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Water Supply, 1950-1969 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Wilderness/Forests, New York, Publications, 1958; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Wilderness, Miscellaneous, 1950-1958 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Wilderness, Miscellaneous, 1959-1967 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Wilderness Policy, Congressional Record, 1st Session, 88th Congress, 1963 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - The Wilderness Society The Living Wilderness, 1959 (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Wildlife Management Institute, Publication, 1962 June (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Wildlife Protection/Animal Rights, 1947; 1964; Undated (Box 3 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Adirondacks, 1955-1978 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Atoms, 1962; 1967 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - The Authors Guild, Inc., Standard Contract, 1972 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Calling All Citizens, Correspondence Evaluation, 1964 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Citizens to Save the Adirondack Park, 1972; 1976 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Conservation, Miscellaneous, 1965-1973 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Constitutional Council for the Forest Preserve, 1965-1966 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Constitutional Council for the Forest Preserve, 1966-1967 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Constitutional Council for the Forest Preserve, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - County Government, 1961 November (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Defenders of Wildlife, 1972 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Defenders of Wildlife, 1973 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - DNA-Government Controls, 1971-1975 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - DNA-SUNYA Involvement, 1976-1977 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Environmental Conservation, Miscellaneous Articles and Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Environmental Policy Issues, Miscellaneous, 1974-1977; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Farming, 1948-1949 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - High Pay, Notes, 1975-1977 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Highway Beautification, 1965 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Institute for Public Policy Alternatives Chronica, [signed by Jerry Egerton], 1994 October (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - International Relations-general, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - International Relations-general, Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Kids' Constitutional Assembly, 1937 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Kodak, Pictures, etc., Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Koe, Walter R., Ducks, Clippings and Photographs, 1961-1963 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Megalopolis, 1962 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Metropolitan Studies, 1964-1965 (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1956-1971; Undated (Box 4 (7-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Nature Conservancy, Activism, 1954-1958 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Nature Conservancy, Activism, 1954-1958 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - New York Times-Redwood article, 1976 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Nature Conservancy-Ecological Studies, 1961-1968 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - New York City Politics, Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - New York Environmental News, 1979 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Project Chariot-Alaskan Explosion, 1959-1962 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Radiation, 1958 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 8)
    Includes clippings [folder 1 of 2].
  - Tivoli Park Nature Sanctuary, 1958 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Washington Capital Info, 1947 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - We Couldn't Find the Word, Undated (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Zero Population Growth, 1951-1973 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 12-13)
  - Overpopulation-Notes, Clippings and Proposals, 1965-1971 (Box 5 (7-Subject Files), Folder 14)
- Printed Materials, 1932-1959; 8; 1.33 cubic ft.
  This series consists of magazine and journal issues with articles by Rienow. Also included are teachers' manuals for Rienow's textbooks, American Problems Toda y and American Government in Today's World.
  Arranged alphabetically by publication title.
  - American Federationist, "What They Say", 1941 July (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 1)
  - American Government in Today's World, Teacher's Manual, Undated (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 2)
  - American Legion Magazine, "They Call It Drinking Water!", 1958 October (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 3)
  - American Legion Magazine, "The American Eagle-Is It Doomed?", 1959 December (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 4)
  - American Problems Today, Teacher's Manual, 1955; 1958 (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 5)
  - Calling All Citizens, Tests and Suggestions for Developing an Evaluation Program, Undated (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 6)
  - The Citizenship Journal, "Responsible Citizenship", 1947 Spring (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 7)
  - "The Fifth French Republic", 1959 (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 8)
  - Harper's Magazine, "The Day the Taps Run Dry", 1958 October (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 9)
  - Harper's Magazine, "Why Spoil the Adirondacks?", 1959 October (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 10)
  - Hi-Y at Work: A Guide to Legislative Proposals, 1941 (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 11)
  - New York State Education, "School and Statehouse", 1938 February (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 12)
  - New York State Education, "Law and Laymen", 1938 March (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 13)
  - New York State Education, "Plain People and Public Problems", 1938 April (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 14)
  - New York State Education, "High School Forums: A Treacherous Taboo", 1938 May (Box 1 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 15)
  - New York State Education, "High School Forums: Creating Civic Consciousness", 1938 June (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 1)
  - New York State and Local Government, Text by Robert Rienow, 1959 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 2)
  - New York State College Alumni Quarterly, "We Are Not Alone", 1942 April (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 3)
  - Outdoor America, "No Voice Crying for the Wilderness", 1940 March (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 4)
  - "Pied Pipers of Exploitation", 1954 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 5)
  - Saturday Review, Rienow Review, 1958 August 16 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 6)
  - School and Society, "Where Teachers Shirk", 1957 July 24 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 7)
  - Secondary Education, 1939 January (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 8)
  - Social Education, "Scholastic Panic", 1939 May (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 9)
  - State College News, Letter to the Editor, 1940 May 3 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 10)
  - State College News, "The Comment States", 1941 May 7 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 11)
  - Today's Living, "New York's Gigantic Thirst", 1959 December 27 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 12)
  - Vital Speeches of the Day, "Screwball Authorities", 1940 February 1 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 13)
  - Vital Speeches of the Day, "Lost: Labor's Love", 1941 May 15 (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 14)
  - The Wisconsin Journal of Education, "Building Character Through Self-Government", 1932 May (Box 2 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 15)
  - Calling All Citizens, Part One, ca. June 1946 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 1)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter I, ca. 1942 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 2)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter I, ca. 1946 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 3)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter II, Undated (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 4)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter II, ca. 1942 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 5)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter III, ca. 1942 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 6)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter III, ca. June 1946 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 7)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter IV, ca. 1942 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 8)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter IV, ca. June 1946 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 9)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter V, ca. 1942 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 10)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter V, ca. June 1946 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 11)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter VI, ca. 1942 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 12)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter VI, ca. June 1946 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 13)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter VII, ca. 1942 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 14)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter VII, ca. June 1946 (Box 3 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 15)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter VIII, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 1)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter IX, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 2)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter IX, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 3)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter X, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 4)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter X, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 5)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XI, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 6)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XI, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 7)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XII, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 8)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XIII, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 9)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XIII, ca. April 1947 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 10)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XIV, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 11)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XIV, ca. April 1947 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 12)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XV, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 13)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XV, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 14)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XVI, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 15)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XVI, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 16)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XVII, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 17)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XVIII, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 18)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XIX, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 19)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XX, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 20)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXI, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 21)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXII, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 22)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXIII, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 23)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXIV, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 24)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXV, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 25)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXVI, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 26)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXVIII, ca. 1947 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 27)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXIX, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 28)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXX, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 29)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXXI, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 30)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXXIII, ca. 1942 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 31)
  - Calling All Citizens, Chapter XXXV, ca. June 1946 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 32)
  - Calling All Citizens, Bibliography, ca. 1947 (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 33)
  - Calling All Citizens, Review, Anderson Howard, Undated (Box 4 (8-Printed Materials), Folder 34)
- Audio Tapes, 1970-1973; 9; 0.67 cubic ft.
  This series contains audio tapes of Robert Rienow's lectures, which were produced and distributed by the Center for Cassette Studies. Many of the cassettes are from the Man Against His Environment lecture series. Some were part of other Center for Cassette Studies series, including The Ecological Spectrum. Each tape has a running time of approximately thirty minutes. Also included are case inserts and library cards that were included with each cassette, as well as catalogs of tapes offered by the Center for Cassette Studies. For preservation reasons, the tapes are stored separately from this supplementary material.
  Arranged alphabetically by series name and title.
  - Center for Cassette Studies, Catalogs, 1972 (Box 1 (9-Audio Tapes), Folder 1)
  - Center for Cassette Studies, Catalogs, 1972 (Box 1 (9-Audio Tapes), Folder 2)
  - Center for Cassette Studies, Catalogs, 1972 (Box 1 (9-Audio Tapes), Folder 3)